303 Columbus Ave Unit 804 Boston, MA 02116 (914)565-1110 https://www.linkedin.com/in/jlveso/ jvelasquezsosa96@gmail.com



Jose Luis Velasquez Sosa

Summary

Motivated Data Scientist with experience in Europe, America and Latin America. Specialized in Natural Language Processing and Data Analytics. Enthusiastic about revolutionary Machine Learning applications and the world they might create. Particularly excited to develop powerful Deep Learning models.

EDUCATION

Maastricht University — BSc. Data Science and Knowledge Engineering

October 2018, Maastricht, NL

- Thesis: Titled "Neural Attention and Morphological Embedding for Contract Element Extraction" built and tested different deep learning models that read contracts in order to build iqueryable databases.
 - \circ Selected for poster publication at Beneleram 2018
- Closing the Loop Project: Built self balancing inverted pendulum by creating a communication protocol between reinforcement learning agents and a robot arm controller.
- Your Move, Hex Project: Built game playing agent which achieved super-human performance for the board game Hex

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Freelancer, Boston

August 2018 - PRESENT

- Empow: Designed AWS architecture and ML algorithms to predict personality type using language.
- Building Als that generate visual arts in collaboration with students at Rhode Island School of Design.
- Brainsolutions.io: Aided on the development team during IBM Watson Build 2018 competition

Ernst & Young, Amsterdam — Research Intern

April 2018 - July 2018

- Built, trained and deployed deep learning models for eDiscovery services. Focused on Contract Element Extraction.
- Performed performance analytics to determine model reliability and performance.

Founders Club Maastricht, Maastricht — Co-Driver

July 2017 - April 2018

- Built internal database to keep track of all events, speakers and members of the organization.
- Organized weekly meeting with the goal to stimulate and grow the entrepreneurial community in Maastricht.
- Organized bi-annual trips around Europe's entrepreneurial hubs (Paris, Lisbon, Berlin, Amsterdam) to learn and inspire local Maastricht entrepreneurs.

Skills

- Data Analysis
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Monte Carlo Simulation
- Python
- Tensorflow
- Java/Scala
- Spark

- R
- SQL
- Amazon Web Services
- Google Cloud Platform